<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A Present remedy for the poor, or, The most probable means to provide well for the poor of the nation to free us in time from paying the poors rates, and deliver us now from the publick nusance of beggars, humbly submitted to the wisdom of the next sessions of Parliament.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1700</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 34 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 9 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A37358</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing D62</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R14418</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12255531</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12255531</idno>
            <idno type="VID">57395</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A37358)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 57395)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 888:13)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A Present remedy for the poor, or, The most probable means to provide well for the poor of the nation to free us in time from paying the poors rates, and deliver us now from the publick nusance of beggars, humbly submitted to the wisdom of the next sessions of Parliament.</title>
                  <author>M. D.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>16 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Jonathan Robinson ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1700.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Bodleian Library.</note>
                  <note>Signed: M.D.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Social service --  Great Britain --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Poverty --  England.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Economic conditions --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-03</date>
            <label>Susie Lorand</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-03</date>
            <label>Susie Lorand</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:57395:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A Preſent Remedy FOR THE POOR: OR, The moſt probable Means to provide well for the Poor of the Nation; to free us in time from paying the Poors Rates; and deliver us now from the publick Nuſance of Beggars.</p>
            <p>Humbly ſubmitted to the Wiſdom of the next Seſſions of Parliament.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON;</hi> Printed for <hi>Jonathan Robinſon</hi> at the Golden Lion in St. <hi>Paul's</hi> Church-Yard. M.DCC. Price 3 <hi>d.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:57395:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:57395:2"/>
            <head>A Preſent REMEDY FOR THE POOR.</head>
            <p>HIS Majeſty's Wiſdom, Care, and Goodneſs in recom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mending this publick Grievance to the Sages of our Nation in the laſt Seſſions of Parliament, deſerves the univerſal Acknowledgment and Thanks of the whole Kingdom. No ſooner was his Mind at liberty from the perplex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Thoughts and heavy Burden of a tedious War, but he appli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed it to the ſtudy of promoting the Peace of his People, by advi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing the redreſs of a known Evil, in theſe words: <hi>I think it would be happy if ſome effectual Expedient could be found for imploying the Poor, which might tend to the great Increaſe of our Manufactures, as well as remove a heavy Burden from the People.</hi> By this and many other Inſtances we may clearly ſee our Happineſs in the injoyment of ſo excellent, valiant, wiſe, and publick-ſpirited a Prince, under whoſe Government and Conduct we may promiſe to our ſelves a laſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Quiet at home, and a flouriſhing Trade abroad: We may promiſe to our ſelves all the Bleſſings of a happy People, if we could be as unanimous and diligent in obſerving our Duties and Obli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gations, as he is vigilant and careful in minding us, and performing all that is required from him in that high Station of Honor and Truſt, where a divine and ſavourable Providence to us, our Religion and Nation, hath placed him. But I intend not here to inlarge upon
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:57395:3"/>the deſerved Praiſes of our King, whom <hi>Europe</hi> and the whole World admires for his extraordinary Abilities both in Peace and War; and who with much more Reaſon and Juſtice might claim the glorious Sirname of GREAT, for having ſaved three Kingdoms from utter Ruin, than the Vanity of others hath aſſum'd it, for having deſtroy'd multitudes of Mankind. My buſineſs in theſe Lines is, to lay open to the wiſe Governours of our Nation this great Grievance of the Poor, which his Majeſty recommended to the Conſideration of the laſt Parliament, and which hitherto con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinues without Redreſs. A growing Grievance that is as diſgrace<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful to our wiſe and reformed Nation, as it is troubleſome to us all, tho we our ſelves are exempted from the ſmart of Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verty. I ſhall alſo venture to offer, with all ſubmiſſion to the Wiſdom of the Government, the moſt probable, or perhaps the only means likely to ſucceed to remedy this publick Nuſance, and what Advantages we may in time procure to our ſelves and Nation by taking the Method I propoſe.</p>
            <p>I need not tell you that Nature, as well as Chriſtianity, calls upon us to commiſerate the Wants and Sufferings of our own kind; and we are taught by the Birds of the Air, to ſupply out of our Abundance the Neceſſities of our own Species. That Bird is moſt remarkable, mentioned by the Royal Prophet, <hi>Pſal.</hi> 104.17. and named by him <hi>Chaſidah,</hi> the merciful Bird, becauſe it is an excel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lent Example among natural Beings, to recommend Charity and Liberality: For as it is reported, the young will not only fetch Food for the old, but bear them upon their Wings, when helpleſs. And of the Eagle it is ſaid, That it is ſo noble, as to call the reſt of the Birds round about to partake of that Plenty that Provi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence vouchſafes it. However, Reaſon can tell us that our wiſe Benefactor having created the World, and the Bleſſings of it, for the general uſe of Mankind; If his Providence appears partial in the diſtribution of its Gifts, 'tis not with a deſign that we ſhould ingroſs them to our ſelves, but learn to imitate our good God, by imparting them to others, who are in want. Stewards therefore we are, and not Proprietors of our Enjoyments; and the intent of our liberal Maker is, that we ſhould convey what we have received from his bountiful Hand, to ſuch Objects of Cha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity as we meet with in our mortal Race; and the more liberal our
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:57395:3"/>God is to us, the more free we ought to be to them. But the whole Body of our Religion, as it is the Product of pure Grace, and a divine Charity, calls upon us, and injoyns us with many Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſes to incourage our Liberalities to the Poor and Needy, and frequently to extend our Charity anſwerable to the heavenly Bounty. Nay, all our expectations of Forgiveneſs of Sins, of the Mercies of our Redeemer, and of the future Rewards, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pend in ſome meaſure upon our Favor and Bounty to the poor Members of Chriſt's myſtical Body, whoſe Indigency a wiſe Providence lays daily before our eyes, that we may by their Aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance and Relief lay up for our ſelves a good foundation for a fu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture State, and make our ſelves Friends, that is, oblige God their Redeemer, and the holy Angels their Guardian-Spirits, to lend us alſo in requital their aſſiſting hand in times of want and dan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger. But I hope I need not inlarge upon this Exhortation to Charity. Our Nation has always been noted for Liberality to Foreigners in diſtreſs, and 'tis not probable it will be leſs boun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiful to its own Natives. How many excellent Laws have been made for that purpoſe, for the continual Relief of the Indi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gent in every Precinct. I may ſay that the Charity of the Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion hath proceede in theſe latter days to an exceſs; inſomuch that many Poor truſting to it, wholly neglect the other means appointed and required by God and Reaſon to recruit their Wants. It belongs therefore to Wiſdom, and our Chriſtian Prudence, to di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rect, as well as to incourage our Charity to the Poor, and pitch upon a right Method to relieve their Neceſſities; ſuch a Method as may be agreeable with the ſtate and condition of the Nation, and may incourage Trade, the chief Source of Plenty.</p>
            <p>Poverty is a univerſal Cry and Complaint both in City and Country. Divers Families have bin brought into diſtreſs by the Evils and Miſchiefs of the Times, the Caſualties of War, and ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral other human Accidents. And like the miſerable Cripple of the Pool of <hi>Betheſda,</hi> Poverty is of it ſelf helpleſs, not able to move without the aſſiſtance of others. And tho it ſharpens In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duſtry to contrive new Inventions, 'tis in ſuch Caſes as when it is not altogether deſpirited by the want of all Neceſſaries, but hath a convenient ſupply of means and life to ſtir and act. Herein Charity is the more oblig'd to diſcover it ſelf, becauſe it is to help ſuch as
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:57395:4"/>are both willing, and ſtrive to help themſelves out of the Calami<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty; and in this caſe all its Proceedings and Liberalities are crown<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and rewarded with ſucceſs, and a double Bleſſing.</p>
            <p>Indeed Poverty in it ſelf is an Evil of that magnitude, that we need no artificial Glaſs to increaſe and inlarge it to our Eye. It is attended by ſo many bad Circumſtances, that may eaſily move our Compaſſion, and oblige rational Beings to indeavour to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>move it both from the publick Society, as well as from our ſelves. Were there nothing elſe but the Clamors and mournful Out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cries of the Poor that daily fill our Ears, and the ſenſe of their urging Neceſſities, and of their Families; were there nothing but their Nakedneſs and Miſery, this would be ſufficient to render the publick Poverty grievous to us as well as to them. But it is a grand and chief Cauſe of many other Miſchiefs among us.</p>
            <p>Firſt, it is the Cauſe of many Robberies, Houſe-breakings, Mur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders, and other Villanies, to which Poverty prompts Perſons who are in want, and by that means renders our living and dealings in City and Country the more unſafe. And I am perſwaded that a great many who are executed every Seſſions and Aſſizes, would never have committed ſuch Wickedneſs, if Poverty had not dri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven them to ſuch abominable Actions.</p>
            <p>It is the Cauſe of Irreligion, and Ignorance of our Duty; for ſuch as are deſperately poor, ſeldom or never mind inſtruction, nor the ſtudy of Religion: they are brought up as Heathens, and the want of Neceſſaries takes up all their thoughts how to pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vide Bread; ſo that they have no time to think upon God or Eter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nity, nor the way that leads thither. It drives many to the ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſity of begging. It incourages Idleneſs, and makes ſeveral whoſe ſtrength and abilities might render them uſeful Members of the Society, to be not only uſeleſs, but pernicious and miſchievous. I need not reckon the other many Evils that Poverty and Beg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ging brings upon us. The number of Beggars increaſes daily, our Streets ſwarm with this kind of People, and their boldneſs and im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pudence is ſuch, that they often beat at our Doors, ſtop Perſons in the ways, and are ready to load us with Curſes and Imprecations, if their Deſires be not ſpeedily anſwer'd. Beſides, it is reported of the common Beggars, that they have their Meetings and Rende<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vouz, where what they have got by their lazy Trade, they can ſpend
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:57395:4"/>freely in Debauchery, Drunkenneſs, and other Sins. By this means the Charity of good People is ſtrangely miſapplied, to the diſhonor of God, and the diſgrace of Religion among us; and theſe ordinary Beggars hinder us from regulating and diſpoſing of our Charity upon the right Objects.</p>
            <p>For the remedying of this Evil and its woful Conſequences, it is needful to imploy our Poor according to the antient and known Laws of the Government, and not only to put in execution the old, but to make ſuch new as may ſtop the increaſe of this beg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ging Trade. It is needful that our wiſe Governors would con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſider how to diſpoſe of theſe poor People, and confine them to Work-houſes, where they may be furniſh'd with neceſſary Tools, and oblig'd to get their living in a lawful way. But the great dif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficulty is how to proceed in the diſpoſing of ſuch vaſt numbers of both Sexes and of all Ages, and how to raiſe a Fund to ſupply the wants of ſo many thouſands.</p>
            <p>I anſwer, That there is every year a million of Mony collected in this Kingdom from all Pariſhes for the relief of their Poor; and if this were rightly applied to the imploying, inſtead of buying them preſent Neceſſaries, it would be ſufficient not only to provide them Tools and other things needful to keep them at work, but that, together with the Product and Advantage of their Work, would anſwer all their Neceſſities, and ſupply all their Wants. But the Difficulty is, how and in what manner to proceed. I am not igno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant, but know perfectly well what Methods are obſerv'd in <hi>Holland</hi> and <hi>France;</hi> where 'tis of late days that Beggars, unleſs they belong to Religious Houſes, are not ſuffer'd; and all Perſons never ſo mean are provided for, without the gathering of ſuch vaſt Rates as among us. If in laying down the beſt means, as I conceive, to provide for our Engliſh Poor, I vary from foreign Methods in ſome things, 'tis becauſe our Conſtitution and Government differs much from theirs, and the Evil is greater among us than it was among them, and therefore requires a Remedy anſwerable.</p>
            <p>Firſt, as it is needful to imploy our Poor, and to ſet them to work, there is a neceſſity that they ſhould be confin'd to a certain Houſe where they may have all Conveniencies for Life and Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ploiment. The Work-houſes that are already built, are not ſo convenient as may be contriv'd for ſuch a vaſt number of Poor
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:57395:5"/>as are among us. I offer therefore to give the Model of ſuch a Houſe as ſhall not be for State, nor to ſhew the Grandure of our Nation, but ſhall be for Uſe, and capacious enough to contain and imploy two thouſand Perſons in daily Labor. Let ſuch a Houſe be erected near the City of <hi>London,</hi> as a Model for all the reſt; I ſuppoſe that three ſuch Houſes will be ſufficient to contain all the Poor of this great City and <hi>Weſtminſter.</hi> And in imitation of the Metropolis, let all other Cities erect for themſelves ſuch conve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nient Workhouſes for all ſorts of Trades, and to imploy and improve the Growth of the Country: for without ſuch a Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>finement, lazy People, uſed to begging, will not take any pains.</p>
            <p>This Houſe muſt be under the Command of a Governour, De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puty-Governour, and other inferiour Officers, choſen in time from the poor People, who are to be kept in hopes of riſing to Honour and Authority in the Houſe, by their Induſtry, Diligence, and other good Behaviour.</p>
            <p>The Governour and Deputy-Governour are to be choſen firſt by the Juſtices, and Magiſtrates of every County; and the other inferiour Officers by the Governour and Conſent of the Houſe.</p>
            <p>Let the Pariſhes give in the number of the Poor who have con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtant relief, when the Houſes are built. Let them ſend them that are chargeable, with their whole Families to ſuch Houſes, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing directed by the Juſtices, or Perſons appointed by Authority, what Pariſhes are to agree to put their Poor together; the num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers of ſuch Poor to be in every Houſe, upwards of a thouſand, and not exceeding two thouſand or thereabouts.</p>
            <p>The Governour's Office ſhall be to buy Neceſſaries, to provide Wool, Flax, and other Commodities; to take charge of the Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple; to ſee that every one labors; to receive and take an account of their Work when done; to pay them their Wages; to be anſwerable for all things; to have Authority in his Houſe as a Juſtice of Peace, and to puniſh with the conſent of other Officers all Miſdemeanors, not injuring neither Life nor Limb.</p>
            <p>Let there be in every ſuch Work-houſe a Chaplain, a Reader who is to be a School-maſter, a Phyſician who is to be a Doctor, Apothecary and Surgeon, a Butcher to buy and provide Food, a Brewer, Baker, and Cooks convenient: Some of which may be taken out of the poor People.</p>
            <pb n="9" facs="tcp:57395:5"/>
            <p>The Houſe is to be built in ſuch a manner upon waſte Ground, or Common, or other convenient place, with neceſſary Gardens be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longing to it, where all Trades are to be diſtinct, with the Spin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning-rooms, Infirmary for Maim'd and Cripples, for Old and una<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble to work, and a Nurſery for Baſtards and Orphans; with a Chappel of an oval Figure, with Galleries, round Theatrewiſe; the Pulpit and Desk near the middle: the Model I offer to give, able to contain greater numbers than any of our Churches in a leſſer Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paſs: The Miniſters and School maſters Lodgings at one end, the Apothecaries at the other. By this means care will be taken both of their Souls and Bodies.</p>
            <p>All the Poor to be lodg'd at the diſcretion of the Governour, to be provided at the publick Charge, with Clothes all of one color in every Houſe; Linen, Tools, Beds and Beddings, with other Conveniencies. And they are to fetch from the Governor or his De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puty, Wool, Flax, Hemp, Iron, Leather, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and when return'd, to be allowed as other Maſters give, or rather more. So that unleſs ſuch as are able to work employ themſelves, they are not to eat.</p>
            <p>Laws are to be preſcrib'd to every Houſe, which they muſt re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligiouſly obſerve; ſuch Laws as are agreeable with our holy Religi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, the Laws of the Land, and the good and peace of ſuch Socie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties. And ſuch as are not able to work, to be provided for; but what every one can do, he is to be directed by the Governours, and furniſh'd with Materials accordingly; for the Governor is to have an overſight over all the Offices of his Houſe, to adviſe, di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rect, incourage every one to do his Duty.</p>
            <p>And for the better managing of a Trade, it is convenient, that four or more Merchants in <hi>London</hi> ſhould aſſociat to furniſh and take off ſuch Commodities and Manufactures as are there made, and in the Cuſtody of the Governors in their ſeveral Ware-hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes in the ſaid Great Houſe; and that theſe Merchants ſhould have their Correſpondents in ſeveral Parts of <hi>England</hi> to buy off ſuch Manufactures made, ſome for ready Mony, ſome upon truſt, as they can agree, and vent the ſame abroad, and have Returns.</p>
            <p>The Governors are to keep an account of all ſuch Monies re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived and paid, and to whom; what Benefit is made of the Work, and to be anſwerable to the Juſtices at their Seſſions.</p>
            <pb n="10" facs="tcp:57395:6"/>
            <p>The Governors ſhall receive from each Pariſh, weekly or month<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, what each Pariſh was wont to pay to their ſeveral Poor for ſome years, until a ſtock of Mony can be raiſed; and to prevent Frauds, ſevere Penalties muſt be impoſed upon Offenders, and an ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count muſt be publiſh'd and printed yearly, that the Nation may ſee that there is no cozenage.</p>
            <p>Let every Governor imploy ſome in making of Sails, Ropes, Nets, and other things for Shipping and Fiſhing; and when they have Youths able and willing for the Seas, let them out of the publick Stock buy one or more Boats, or convenient Buſſes or Veſſels at Sea, to belong to every Houſe; and that all the Fiſh taken ſhall be brought thither, if not too far from the Seas, and diſpos'd of at the Governour's Diſcretion, allowing a Subſiſtence and Salary to their Agents. By this means the Shipping and Fiſhing Trade will be incouraged.</p>
            <p>And if at any time poor Families have no Work, who be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>long not to theſe Houſes, there they ſhall be furniſh'd with Wool, Hemp, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and other Materials for them and their Fami<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lies. So that theſe Houſes may imploy many more than are ſhut within the Walls.</p>
            <p>If any are ſturdy, unruly, or refuſe to work, or run away, a courſe may be taken to remedy that and other accidents. A ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vere Law muſt be made to puniſh Officers of Pariſhes that neglect to carry them back, and others that offer to give them any relief; and ſuch Penalties and Fines are to be return'd and paid in to the Governors of ſuch Houſes, together with the Perſons of ſuch Run<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>aways. No maintenance is to be allowed them, but within the Houſe, and that proportion'd to their deſervings. If they run away again, let them be whip'd publickly, and be carried back as often as they ſhall thus eſcape.</p>
            <p>Now if any poor Families be not able to ſubſiſt by reaſon of Children, and their Parents cannot well be ſpar'd from the Neigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bourhood, becauſe of their handy work, let the eldeſt of their Children be ſent to theſe Houſes; firſt taught to read, write, and cipher, and to be put to ſuch Trades and Maſters in theſe Houſes as may teach them their Craft and Skill. So that the Officers of every Pariſh ſhall not need to give any weekly allowance to ſuch poor Parents; and in a little time, when a conſiderable Fund may
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:57395:6"/>be rais'd by ſuch Trade and Working, no Poors-Rates will be any more gather'd in the Nation.</p>
            <p>If any ſturdy Beggars be incorrigible, let the Governors, with the conſent of the Juſtices at the publick Seſſions, have Power to tran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſport ſuch unruly Perſons beyond Sea, if they be young and fit for Travelling to our Weſtern Plantations, or to ſend them to ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rer Houſes to a ſtraiter Confinement, there to be dealt with ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to Law, till they ſhall reſolve to amend.</p>
            <p>Let every ſuch Houſe have convenient Privileges granted to it to incourage the Poor to be induſtrious. Let their inferiour Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers be all annually choſen by themſelves, with the aſſiſtance of the Governor and his Deputy, who alone muſt be appointed by the Government.</p>
            <p>Let the Commodities and Manufactures made in ſuch Houſes be freed from Cuſtoms, or pay not ſo much as others when ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ported out of the Land, for a limited time.</p>
            <p>Let it be in the Power of the Governors of ſuch Houſes near Seaport-Towns, and other places, with the conſent of ſuch Perſons of their Societies, as will of their own accord, to plant in the Weſt-<hi>Indies</hi> and ſuch Plantations, to belong to the Governors and their Houſes, and to the Parties ſo ſent, as they ſhall agree. By which means they may vent a great many of their Manufactures made in their Work-houſes, and have Returns in Sugars, Tobac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>co, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Let there be a Prebendary or two belong to each Houſe, or a Benefice or ſpiritual Living adjoining, for the incouragement of the Miniſter and School-maſter, and let that be to them inſtead of a Salary to maintain them. Let ſome other publick Incourage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment or Income be appointed for the Phyſician to incourage him alſo.</p>
            <p>Let every Child within the Houſe be firſt taught to read, write cipher, and other neceſſary Learning, with the Principles of true Religion, by the Miniſter and his Reader, or School-maſter: and let conſtant Catechiſing, and expounding upon the Catechiſm in a fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miliar way, be practis'd every holy day and Sunday in the after<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>noon; and Prayers twice a week on the working days, or oftner if it be convenient. And let all within the Houſe come or be brought to the Divine Service, at leaſt every Sabbath Day, if Sick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs hinders not.</p>
            <pb n="12" facs="tcp:57395:7"/>
            <p>Let all within the Houſe live in a loving and courteous manner, abſtaining from Swearing, Curſing Scolding, or opprobrious Language, according to the Laws there to be obſerved. And let them buy their Neceſſaries of one another, that their Mony may there cir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culate within themſelves, and incourage their Induſtry and Labor.</p>
            <p>And for a greater incouragement to ſuch charitable Houſes, let the Governor of his Deputy, and other Officers, with the Appro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bation of the Juſtices of the County, have Power to buy Lands, Tenements, and other Rents, which may belong to ſuch Houſes for ever, and to receive the benefit of any Gifts or Legacies, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> which religious Perſons ſhall beſtow upon them for the Repair of their Houſes, and the greater incouragement of the Poor.</p>
            <p>Now for the maintenance of ſuch Governors and Deputy-Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernors, without taking any thing from the publick Monies, I of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fer to lay down an eaſy and practicable Method, which I doubt not but will be approv'd of. And beſides, when the Trade ſhall grow conſiderable in theſe Houſes, let them have but the ordinary Fees of Factors and Agents beyond Sea, or at home, that will greatly in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creaſe their firſt Incomes, and cauſe them to live with Splendor and Plenty, without diminiſhing any thing from the Poors Mony, or the Publick Stock.</p>
            <p>And for the intire Suppreſſion of the begging Trade, let it be lawful for all poor Priſoners, who have nothing to ſubſiſt upon but Charity, to turn themſelves over to theſe Work-houſes to get their living; and what they can ſpare out of their Work, let it be im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployed to pay their Creditors, as the Wiſdom of the Nation ſhall think fit.</p>
            <p>But how ſhall ſuch Houſes be erected, and who ſhall pay for the ſame?</p>
            <p>I anſwer, Several eaſy and practicable Means may be propoſed, for the raiſing ſufficient Sums of Mony for the ſpeedy building of Houſes.</p>
            <p>Firſt let a Collection be made by way of a Brief in every Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty for the benefit of that County; and the Monies ſo collected be return'd into the hands of the Sheriff, or his Deputy, to pay off the Workmen and buy Materials.</p>
            <p>Let all Commutations for Whoredom and Baſtardy, be likewiſe converted to this publick Uſe, and the Mony to remain in the
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:57395:7"/>hands of the Chancellor or Official for this purpoſe, to be com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded from thence by the order of the Government. And let a ſtrict Inquiry be made, and all Perſons guilty be oblig'd either to fine or do penance. Truly this Mony can never be better imployed; for I have ſeen in the diſpenſing Deeds of the Eccleſiaſtical Courts, that it is to be imployed, <hi>Ad uſum Pauperum, &amp; alios pios uſus:</hi> To the uſe of the Poor, and other religious Uſes.</p>
            <p>Let all Prebendaries and Dignities of the Church, which ſhall be hereafter beſtowed, pay a year or two years Rent, or a cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain Proportion, to be charg'd at the Diſcretion of our Parliament, and let this continue until ſuch time as theſe Houſes ſo erected be paid for. And let all Benefices above 100 <hi>l. per annum</hi> pay the Overplus into the Biſhops hands, or his Receiver, for two years af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Induction. And let the Clerk oblige himſelf by Bond, or be forc'd by Law to pay the ſame, and let him be inſtituted and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ducted upon that condition.</p>
            <p>Let all ſuch as now injoy great Benefices, multiplicity of Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bendaries and other Pluralities, be charg'd to this pious Work as the Wiſdom of our Parliament ſhall think fit. But all Deans, Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nons, Prebendaries, and Sine Cures, ought in reaſon to contribute: For theſe Eſtates were firſt granted by the religious Donors, <hi>ad per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>petuam Eleemoſynam;</hi> not only for the incouragement of Learning, for the maintenance of the Service of God, for a more ſplendid Government of the Church, but for the Benefit and Comfort of the Poor in every County, where they had no Laws then to gather Taxes for their relief.</p>
            <p>Let alſo ſome certain Fines to be impos'd by the Government, at the Aſſizes and Seſſions, and in Courts of Judicature, upon Offenders, be appropriated to the Building of theſe convenient Houſes in the ſeveral Counties where the Offences were committed.</p>
            <p>And for a more effectual carrying on of this good Work, let four or more Perſons be appointed as publick Commiſſioners, to puſh it on and bring it to perfection. Let them divide the Nation between them, and viſit every County, and there adviſe with the Juſtices for convenient places to erect ſuch Work-houſe for the Poor. Let them be authoris'd by the Government to take waſte Ground, to agree with the Proprietors and Workmen, and to appoint, with the conſent of the Juſtices, Governors and
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:57395:8"/>Deputy-Governors, to overſee the Workmen, and haſten the Building, according to the firſt Pattern to be erected near the City of <hi>London.</hi> And let them make ſuch Regulations as ſhall be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venient. And let them order a ſtock of Hemp, and other Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modities and Monies to be deliver'd and paid to the Governors of the Poor out of the Monies collected in each County. And for their incouragement, let ſuch Perſons have ſome publick Office of Profit or Advantage beſtowed upon them to incourage them, and defray their Charges, that what they do may be <hi>gratis</hi> in relation to the Poor, or their Stock, and nothing may be diminiſh'd out of it, but wholly ſpent for the relief and imployment of ſuch poor Perſons whoſe whole Families, may be admitted, and all put to work according to their ſeveral Abilities and Ages.</p>
            <p>Some other eaſy Methods may be contrived to raiſe Mony for the building of theſe Houſes, which may not in any wiſe burden the Commonalty of the Nation; For inſtance, let all great Offices in Law, and other profitable imploys in Church and State, be charg'd with the payment of ſome Proportion of ſuch large Revenues for this publick Good. I doubt not but thoſe worthy Gentlemen whom God hath bleſs'd with plentiful Eſtates either in Church, Law, or Government, will not grudg to allow ſomething out of their abundance to this pious Work, for the eaſement of their Neighbours and themſelves.</p>
            <p>If theſe Propoſals may be accepted, and the Methods here laid down be found agreeing with the Wiſdom of our Governors, as it is both rational, juſt, and feaſible; I doubt not but to ſhew ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Expedient for the raiſing of a conſiderable Sum of Mony, with the general Applauſe of the whole Nation, if any of theſe former Methods diſpleaſe the Humor or Stingineſs of ſuch as are deſired to contribute; or if the Fund ſo rais'd be not ſufficient to com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pleat this great Work; that is, to erect the Work-houſes, and buy in to them a ſufficient Stock of the Growth of the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try, as may imploy all the idle and lazy Poor of the Nation. Let there be an inquiry made into two or three grand Abuſes in the Nation, and ſuch as are found guilty, be depriv'd of their unjuſt gain<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> that is, what they for ſome years have uſurp'd and enjoyed contrary to the known Laws of the Land, and be oblig'd to quit and to refund for two or three years back what they have thus
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:57395:8"/>taken: I dare be bold to promiſe a conſiderable Sum either into the King's Exchequer, or for the carrying on this Work.</p>
            <p>And for the City of <hi>London,</hi> for which I have always had a particular Affection, having receiv'd there my firſt Education; as the Poor in the adjacent parts thereabouts are more numerous than in any other part, and the number of Beggars, and the Evil great<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er, ſo larger Sums of Mony are required for the erecting theſe neceſſary Work-houſes. I ſuppoſe no leſs than three may be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quired in and about this large City, for the containing of all the poor Families. One in the City and Liberties, another about <hi>Spittle-fields,</hi> or towards <hi>Wapping,</hi> and another for <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> and that part. I offer to the worthy and honourable Governors of this noble City, if they ſhall pleaſe to liſten to my Propoſals, to ſhew them an eaſy Method to raiſe Mony for the time to come, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out burdening their Neighbours, ſufficient for the building and pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paring all theſe Workhouſes, and to give my pains freely in the management and carrying on of this Work, without expectation of any other Reward but the Honor and great ſatisfaction of ſeeing it brought to perfection.</p>
            <p>I underſtand that the religious Governors of this City, impower'd by Law, have taken Methods already to imploy their Poor, have raiſed Mony, hired large Houſes in <hi>Biſhopſgate-ſtreet,</hi> and are pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paring them for their Reception, and have brought this Buſineſs to a tolerable perfection, within their Juriſdiction. Let them in proſc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cution of their judicious Indeavors, appoint Officers to ſuch a num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber as they can well manage. Let a Care be taken of Religion a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong the Poor, that we may expect a greater Bleſſing upon the publick Proceedings; and let an Act of Parliament be deſired, to confirm and grant ſuch things as ſhall be thought neceſſary for the carrying on of this pious Work. And let there be a Stock of all Commodities grow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in our Country be provided, to imploy ſuch Poor as are within and without the Houſe. I doubt not but to ſee this buſineſs compleated to the Satisfaction of all the Inhabitants whoin a ſhort time will rejoice to ſee their Mony ſo well imployed.</p>
            <p>I intreat them therefore to conſider, and ſeriouſly to weigh what I have here offer'd, how reaſonable it is that it is neceſſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry that the lazy Poor ſhould be confin'd and oblig'd to work either for want of Food, or by ſome other Reſtraint and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pulſion.
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:57395:9"/>That ſuch Houſes being built and regulated in this man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner, under a Governor and his Deputy, are the moſt convenient for this purpoſe. That this Method tends to the Glory of God, the Inſtruction as well as Imployment and Maintenance of the Poor, to the freeing of the Nation from all lazy and idle Beg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gars, to the increaſe of Trade, to the augmenting in time of his Majeſty's Revenues, to remove out of our ſight a great Eyeſore and Grievance. It tends to eaſe us from the great burden of thoſe Rates that we pay to the Poor, more to incourage their lazineſs, than to relieve their wants. It tends to the Glory and great Advantage of our Trading Nation, and to the Honor of our Reformation. And this buſineſs may be ſo carried on, that no Perſon ſhall find him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf either burden'd or aggriev'd. And if any Objection, which I can't at preſent foreſee, ſhall be made againſt this Expedient to pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vide for our Poor, I offer to anſwer it, and to prove that it tends wholly to the publick Good more than to any private Intereſt. Nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther can there be any imbezling or diverting of the publick Monies from the appointed Uſes, becauſe ſuch as ſhall be intruſted, may be narrowly lookt after; and no longer are they to receive the ſame, than they free every Pariſh from their preſent Burden of the Poor. And I judg it more reaſonable for us to truſt ſuch judicious Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nors with a prudent management of the Poors Mony for their good, than to put it into the hands of ſuch idle and lazy Prodigals (as we now do) who truſt wholly upon the Sweat and Labors, and to the forced Charity and Benevolence of their poor Neighbors, and laviſh it often at a ſtrange rate. And theſe Houſes, the fuller they are, and the more hands to work, the richer they and their Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nors will grow: So that in a few years they will take away all our Poor without contribution, who will be able to ſubſiſt plentifully and better within theſe Houſes than ordinary People without, and free us in time from the payment of all Poors Rates.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>I pray God direct our wiſe Governors in this and all their other Conſul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tations, for his Glory, his Majeſty's Honor, tho Nations Credit, the Increaſe of true Religion, and the publick Good.</hi> Amen.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>M. D.</signed>
            </closer>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
